{"problemsArray": [
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(4x + 9)} + {1}/{(x + 8)} \u003d {2(x + 4)}/{(4x + 9)(x + 8)}\\)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 9)(x + 8)\n\\(3(x + 8) + (4x + 9) \u003d 2(x + 4)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 8) + (4x + 9) - 2(x + 4) \u003d 0\\)\n5(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(3x + 10)} + {1}/{(2x + 3)} \u003d {(4x + 1)}/{(3x + 10)(2x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 10)(2x + 3)\n\\(2(2x + 3) + (3x + 10) \u003d (4x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(2x + 3) + (3x + 10) - (4x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{3(x + 1)} + {3}/{(x + 8)} \u003d {(2x + 11)}/{(x + 1)(x + 8)}\\)", "answer": "4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 8)\n\\({(x + 8)}/{3} + 3(x + 1) \u003d (2x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(x + 8)}/{3} + 3(x + 1) - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x - 4)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(2x + 3)} + {1}/{2(x + 1)} \u003d {(x + 8)}/{(2x + 3)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "12", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(x + 1)\n\\({(x + 1)}/{2} + {(2x + 3)}/{2} \u003d (x + 8)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(x + 1)}/{2} + {(2x + 3)}/{2} - (x + 8) \u003d 0\\)\n(x - 12)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n12\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(2x + 7)} + {1}/{(2x + 7)} \u003d {2(x + 1)}/{(2x + 7)(2x + 7)}\\)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 7)(2x + 7)\n\\((2x + 7) + (2x + 7) \u003d 2(x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((2x + 7) + (2x + 7) - 2(x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 5)} + {2}/{(x + 8)} \u003d {4(x + 2)}/{(2x + 5)(x + 8)}\\)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(x + 8)\n\\(2(x + 8) + 2(2x + 5) \u003d 4(x + 2)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 8) + 2(2x + 5) - 4(x + 2) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 9) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{3(x + 1)} + {1}/{(x + 9)} \u003d {(x + 5)}/{(x + 1)(x + 9)}\\)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 9)\n\\({2(x + 9)}/{3} + (x + 1) \u003d (x + 5)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({2(x + 9)}/{3} + (x + 1) - (x + 5) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 3)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 4)} + {2}/{(4x + 1)} \u003d {(4x + 9)}/{(x + 4)(4x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(4x + 1)\n\\((4x + 1) + 2(x + 4) \u003d (4x + 9)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((4x + 1) + 2(x + 4) - (4x + 9) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 2)} + {1}/{2(x + 5)} \u003d {(2x + 7)}/{(x + 2)(x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 5)\n\\(2(x + 5) + {(x + 2)}/{2} \u003d (2x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 5) + {(x + 2)}/{2} - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 8)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 9)} + {2}/{3(x + 1)} \u003d {(2x + 11)}/{(x + 9)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-12", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(x + 1)\n\\((x + 1) + {2(x + 9)}/{3} \u003d (2x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 1) + {2(x + 9)}/{3} - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x - 12)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-12\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({4}/{(x + 2)} + {3}/{(x + 11)} \u003d {(4x + 11)}/{(x + 2)(x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-13", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 11)\n\\(4(x + 11) + 3(x + 2) \u003d (4x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(4(x + 11) + 3(x + 2) - (4x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x + 13) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-13\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 5)} + {4}/{(4x + 1)} \u003d {(x + 7)}/{(2x + 5)(4x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(4x + 1)\n\\(2(4x + 1) + 4(2x + 5) \u003d (x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(4x + 1) + 4(2x + 5) - (x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n15(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(x + 11)} + {2}/{(x + 10)} \u003d {(4x + 1)}/{(x + 11)(x + 10)}\\)", "answer": "-51", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 11)(x + 10)\n\\(3(x + 10) + 2(x + 11) \u003d (4x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 10) + 2(x + 11) - (4x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 51) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-51\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({4}/{(3x + 10)} + {1}/{(x + 9)} \u003d {3(x + 2)}/{(3x + 10)(x + 9)}\\)", "answer": "-10", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 10)(x + 9)\n\\(4(x + 9) + (3x + 10) \u003d 3(x + 2)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(4(x + 9) + (3x + 10) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x + 10) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-10\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({4}/{(x + 2)} + {1}/{(x + 1)} \u003d {(x + 6)}/{(x + 2)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 1)\n\\(4(x + 1) + (x + 2) \u003d (x + 6)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(4(x + 1) + (x + 2) - (x + 6) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{2(x + 4)} + {4}/{(x + 3)} \u003d {(4x + 7)}/{(x + 4)(x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 3)\n\\({3(x + 3)}/{2} + 4(x + 4) \u003d (4x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({3(x + 3)}/{2} + 4(x + 4) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x + 9)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 9)} + {1}/{(3x + 11)} \u003d {(3x + 7)}/{(x + 9)(3x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(3x + 11)\n\\(2(3x + 11) + (x + 9) \u003d (3x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(3x + 11) + (x + 9) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(3x + 5)} + {1}/{(x + 3)} \u003d {(3x + 11)}/{(3x + 5)(x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 5)(x + 3)\n\\(3(x + 3) + (3x + 5) \u003d (3x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 3) + (3x + 5) - (3x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 3)} + {3}/{(3x + 7)} \u003d {(4x + 7)}/{(2x + 3)(3x + 7)}\\)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(3x + 7)\n\\(2(3x + 7) + 3(2x + 3) \u003d (4x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(3x + 7) + 3(2x + 3) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n8(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(2x + 5)} + {1}/{(4x + 1)} \u003d {3(x + 2)}/{(2x + 5)(4x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(4x + 1)\n\\((4x + 1) + (2x + 5) \u003d 3(x + 2)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((4x + 1) + (2x + 5) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 1)} + {3}/{(3x + 8)} \u003d {(3x + 10)}/{(2x + 1)(3x + 8)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(3x + 8)\n\\(2(3x + 8) + 3(2x + 1) \u003d (3x + 10)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(3x + 8) + 3(2x + 1) - (3x + 10) \u003d 0\\)\n9(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 7)} + {3}/{(x + 6)} \u003d {(4x + 3)}/{(x + 7)(x + 6)}\\)", "answer": "-30", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 7)(x + 6)\n\\(2(x + 6) + 3(x + 7) \u003d (4x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 6) + 3(x + 7) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 30) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-30\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 9)} + {2}/{(x + 5)} \u003d {2(x + 1)}/{(x + 9)(x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "-13", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(x + 5)\n\\(2(x + 5) + 2(x + 9) \u003d 2(x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 5) + 2(x + 9) - 2(x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 13) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-13\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(x + 4)} + {2}/{(2x + 9)} \u003d {(3x + 10)}/{(x + 4)(2x + 9)}\\)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(2x + 9)\n\\(3(2x + 9) + 2(x + 4) \u003d (3x + 10)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(2x + 9) + 2(x + 4) - (3x + 10) \u003d 0\\)\n5(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(x + 1)} + {1}/{2(2x + 1)} \u003d {(3x + 1)}/{(x + 1)(2x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(2x + 1)\n\\({(2x + 1)}/{2} + {(x + 1)}/{2} \u003d (3x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(2x + 1)}/{2} + {(x + 1)}/{2} - (3x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n-3(x)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({4}/{(2x + 3)} + {1}/{(4x + 5)} \u003d {(x + 6)}/{(2x + 3)(4x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(4x + 5)\n\\(4(4x + 5) + (2x + 3) \u003d (x + 6)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(4(4x + 5) + (2x + 3) - (x + 6) \u003d 0\\)\n17(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(x + 2)} + {1}/{(3x + 7)} \u003d {(2x + 7)}/{(x + 2)(3x + 7)}\\)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(3x + 7)\n\\({(3x + 7)}/{2} + (x + 2) \u003d (2x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(3x + 7)}/{2} + (x + 2) - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n(x - 3)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 2)} + {2}/{(3x + 11)} \u003d {(x + 5)}/{(x + 2)(3x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(3x + 11)\n\\(2(3x + 11) + 2(x + 2) \u003d (x + 5)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(3x + 11) + 2(x + 2) - (x + 5) \u003d 0\\)\n7(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 1)} + {3}/{2(x + 1)} \u003d {(2x + 7)}/{(x + 1)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 1)\n\\((x + 1) + {3(x + 1)}/{2} \u003d (2x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 1) + {3(x + 1)}/{2} - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n(x - 9)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 2)} + {2}/{(2x + 11)} \u003d {(2x + 1)}/{(x + 2)(2x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(2x + 11)\n\\((2x + 11) + 2(x + 2) \u003d (2x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((2x + 11) + 2(x + 2) - (2x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({4}/{(x + 7)} + {1}/{(x + 1)} \u003d {4(x + 2)}/{(x + 7)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 7)(x + 1)\n\\(4(x + 1) + (x + 7) \u003d 4(x + 2)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(4(x + 1) + (x + 7) - 4(x + 2) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 3)} + {1}/{(3x + 10)} \u003d {(x + 9)}/{(2x + 3)(3x + 10)}\\)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(3x + 10)\n\\(2(3x + 10) + (2x + 3) \u003d (x + 9)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(3x + 10) + (2x + 3) - (x + 9) \u003d 0\\)\n7(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{4(x + 2)} + {1}/{(x + 11)} \u003d {1}/{(x + 2)}\\)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)\n\\({3(x + 11)}/{4} + (x + 2) \u003d (x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({3(x + 11)}/{4} + (x + 2) - (x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x - 1)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(3x + 2)} + {1}/{(x + 3)} \u003d {(4x + 5)}/{(3x + 2)(x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 2)(x + 3)\n\\((x + 3) + (3x + 2) \u003d (4x + 5)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 3) + (3x + 2) - (4x + 5) \u003d 0\\)\n0(0x0) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(x + 11)} + {1}/{(x + 2)} \u003d {(2x + 7)}/{(x + 11)(x + 2)}\\)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 11)(x + 2)\n\\(3(x + 2) + (x + 11) \u003d (2x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 2) + (x + 11) - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(2x + 3)} + {1}/{(2x + 1)} \u003d {2(x + 5)}/{(2x + 3)(2x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(2x + 1)\n\\((2x + 1) + (2x + 3) \u003d 2(x + 5)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((2x + 1) + (2x + 3) - 2(x + 5) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x - 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 1)} + {1}/{(x + 3)} \u003d {(2x + 7)}/{(2x + 1)(x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)(x + 3)\n\\(2(x + 3) + (2x + 1) \u003d (2x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 3) + (2x + 1) - (2x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({4}/{(4x + 9)} + {1}/{(x + 4)} \u003d {(4x + 5)}/{(4x + 9)(x + 4)}\\)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 9)(x + 4)\n\\(4(x + 4) + (4x + 9) \u003d (4x + 5)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(4(x + 4) + (4x + 9) - (4x + 5) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(3x + 11)} + {2}/{(x + 5)} \u003d {2(2x + 3)}/{(3x + 11)(x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 11)(x + 5)\n\\((x + 5) + 2(3x + 11) \u003d 2(2x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 5) + 2(3x + 11) - 2(2x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(3x + 11)} + {4}/{(3x + 11)} \u003d {2(x + 1)}/{(3x + 11)(3x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 11)(3x + 11)\n\\(2(3x + 11) + 4(3x + 11) \u003d 2(x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(3x + 11) + 4(3x + 11) - 2(x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n16(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 3)} + {3}/{(x + 10)} \u003d {(2x + 11)}/{(x + 3)(x + 10)}\\)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 10)\n\\((x + 10) + 3(x + 3) \u003d (2x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 10) + 3(x + 3) - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(3x + 8)} + {1}/{(4x + 7)} \u003d {(3x + 7)}/{(3x + 8)(4x + 7)}\\)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 8)(4x + 7)\n\\((4x + 7) + (3x + 8) \u003d (3x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((4x + 7) + (3x + 8) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(2x + 3)} + {1}/{(3x + 10)} \u003d {(2x + 1)}/{(2x + 3)(3x + 10)}\\)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(3x + 10)\n\\((3x + 10) + (2x + 3) \u003d (2x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((3x + 10) + (2x + 3) - (2x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 5)} + {1}/{(2x + 11)} \u003d {(2x + 9)}/{(x + 5)(2x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(2x + 11)\n\\((2x + 11) + (x + 5) \u003d (2x + 9)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((2x + 11) + (x + 5) - (2x + 9) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(2x + 5)} + {2}/{(4x + 11)} \u003d {(4x + 9)}/{(2x + 5)(4x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(4x + 11)\n\\((4x + 11) + 2(2x + 5) \u003d (4x + 9)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((4x + 11) + 2(2x + 5) - (4x + 9) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 9)} + {1}/{(x + 1)} \u003d {3(x + 2)}/{(x + 9)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(x + 1)\n\\((x + 1) + (x + 9) \u003d 3(x + 2)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 1) + (x + 9) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{3(x + 3)} + {2}/{(2x + 9)} \u003d {(3x + 8)}/{(x + 3)(2x + 9)}\\)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(2x + 9)\n\\({(2x + 9)}/{3} + 2(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 8)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(2x + 9)}/{3} + 2(x + 3) - (3x + 8) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x + 3)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 10)} + {2}/{(x + 3)} \u003d {(3x + 7)}/{(x + 10)(x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "-19", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 3)\n\\(2(x + 3) + 2(x + 10) \u003d (3x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 3) + 2(x + 10) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 19) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-19\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 4)} + {1}/{(x + 4)} \u003d {(2x + 3)}/{(x + 4)(x + 4)}\\)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 4)\n\\(2(x + 4) + (x + 4) \u003d (2x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 4) + (x + 4) - (2x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 9) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 3)} + {1}/{(4x + 5)} \u003d {2}/{(4x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 5)\n\\(2(4x + 5) + (x + 3) \u003d 2(x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(4x + 5) + (x + 3) - 2(x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n7(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(2x + 5)} + {1}/{(3x + 5)} \u003d {(x + 10)}/{(2x + 5)(3x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(3x + 5)\n\\({(3x + 5)}/{2} + (2x + 5) \u003d (x + 10)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(3x + 5)}/{2} + (2x + 5) - (x + 10) \u003d 0\\)\n5(x - 1)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{2(x + 1)} + {1}/{4(x + 2)} \u003d {(2x + 11)}/{(x + 1)(x + 2)}\\)", "answer": "-31", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 2)\n\\({3(x + 2)}/{2} + {(x + 1)}/{4} \u003d (2x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({3(x + 2)}/{2} + {(x + 1)}/{4} - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x - 31)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-31\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 11)} + {3}/{(4x + 9)} \u003d {(4x + 11)}/{(2x + 11)(4x + 9)}\\)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 11)(4x + 9)\n\\(2(4x + 9) + 3(2x + 11) \u003d (4x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(4x + 9) + 3(2x + 11) - (4x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n10(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 4)} + {2}/{(x + 10)} \u003d {(x + 6)}/{(x + 4)(x + 10)}\\)", "answer": "-6", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 10)\n\\((x + 10) + 2(x + 4) \u003d (x + 6)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 10) + 2(x + 4) - (x + 6) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 6) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-6\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(x + 4)} + {3}/{(x + 1)} \u003d {4}/{(x + 4)}\\)", "answer": "17", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)\n\\({(x + 1)}/{2} + 3(x + 4) \u003d 4(x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(x + 1)}/{2} + 3(x + 4) - 4(x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x + 17)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n17\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 3)} + {4}/{(x + 3)} \u003d {2(2x + 1)}/{(x + 3)(x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "-13", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 3)\n\\((x + 3) + 4(x + 3) \u003d 2(2x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 3) + 4(x + 3) - 2(2x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 13) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-13\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 5)} + {1}/{2(x + 5)} \u003d {(3x + 1)}/{(x + 5)(x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "23", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 5)\n\\(2(x + 5) + {(x + 5)}/{2} \u003d (3x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 5) + {(x + 5)}/{2} - (3x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x + 23)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n23\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 9)} + {1}/{(x + 7)} \u003d {3(x + 3)}/{(x + 9)(x + 7)}\\)", "answer": "7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(x + 7)\n\\((x + 7) + (x + 9) \u003d 3(x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 7) + (x + 9) - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x + 7) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(x + 4)} + {3}/{2(2x + 1)} \u003d {(3x + 7)}/{(x + 4)(2x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(2x + 1)\n\\({(2x + 1)}/{2} + {3(x + 4)}/{2} \u003d (3x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(2x + 1)}/{2} + {3(x + 4)}/{2} - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x - 1)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 2)} + {3}/{4(x + 1)} \u003d {(3x + 8)}/{(x + 2)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-18", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 1)\n\\(2(x + 1) + {3(x + 2)}/{4} \u003d (3x + 8)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 1) + {3(x + 2)}/{4} - (3x + 8) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x - 18)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-18\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(4x + 3)} + {1}/{3(x + 1)} \u003d {(4x + 1)}/{(4x + 3)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 3)(x + 1)\n\\(3(x + 1) + {(4x + 3)}/{3} \u003d (4x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 1) + {(4x + 3)}/{3} - (4x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 9)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(4x + 5)} + {4}/{(x + 7)} \u003d {(4x + 11)}/{(4x + 5)(x + 7)}\\)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 5)(x + 7)\n\\(3(x + 7) + 4(4x + 5) \u003d (4x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 7) + 4(4x + 5) - (4x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n15(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(x + 3)} + {3}/{2(x + 1)} \u003d {(x + 10)}/{(x + 3)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 1)\n\\({(x + 1)}/{2} + {3(x + 3)}/{2} \u003d (x + 10)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(x + 1)}/{2} + {3(x + 3)}/{2} - (x + 10) \u003d 0\\)\n(x - 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(x + 10)} + {3}/{(x + 9)} \u003d {(4x + 3)}/{(x + 10)(x + 9)}\\)", "answer": "-27", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 10)(x + 9)\n\\(3(x + 9) + 3(x + 10) \u003d (4x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 9) + 3(x + 10) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 27) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-27\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(2x + 5)} + {3}/{2(x + 3)} \u003d {(3x + 5)}/{(2x + 5)(x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(x + 3)\n\\({(x + 3)}/{2} + {3(2x + 5)}/{2} \u003d (3x + 5)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(x + 3)}/{2} + {3(2x + 5)}/{2} - (3x + 5) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 8)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 7)} + {3}/{(3x + 2)} \u003d {(2x + 11)}/{(x + 7)(3x + 2)}\\)", "answer": "-2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 7)(3x + 2)\n\\(2(3x + 2) + 3(x + 7) \u003d (2x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(3x + 2) + 3(x + 7) - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n7(x + 2) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 5)} + {1}/{2(x + 1)} \u003d {(x + 6)}/{(x + 5)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 1)\n\\(2(x + 1) + {(x + 5)}/{2} \u003d (x + 6)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 1) + {(x + 5)}/{2} - (x + 6) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x - 1)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 9)} + {3}/{(3x + 4)} \u003d {(3x + 1)}/{(x + 9)(3x + 4)}\\)", "answer": "-10", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(3x + 4)\n\\((3x + 4) + 3(x + 9) \u003d (3x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((3x + 4) + 3(x + 9) - (3x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n3(x + 10) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-10\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{3(x + 3)} + {2}/{(2x + 3)} \u003d {(3x + 1)}/{(x + 3)(2x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "-21", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(2x + 3)\n\\({2(2x + 3)}/{3} + 2(x + 3) \u003d (3x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({2(2x + 3)}/{3} + 2(x + 3) - (3x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 21)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-21\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 5)} + {4}/{(x + 9)} \u003d {(3x + 10)}/{(2x + 5)(x + 9)}\\)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 5)(x + 9)\n\\(2(x + 9) + 4(2x + 5) \u003d (3x + 10)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 9) + 4(2x + 5) - (3x + 10) \u003d 0\\)\n7(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 9)} + {1}/{(x + 2)} \u003d {(x + 11)}/{(x + 9)(x + 2)}\\)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(x + 2)\n\\((x + 2) + (x + 9) \u003d (x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 2) + (x + 9) - (x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\nx \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(3x + 7)} + {2}/{(4x + 11)} \u003d {(3x + 2)}/{(3x + 7)(4x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 7)(4x + 11)\n\\(3(4x + 11) + 2(3x + 7) \u003d (3x + 2)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(4x + 11) + 2(3x + 7) - (3x + 2) \u003d 0\\)\n15(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 3)} + {1}/{(x + 6)} \u003d {(3x + 7)}/{(2x + 3)(x + 6)}\\)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(x + 6)\n\\(2(x + 6) + (2x + 3) \u003d (3x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 6) + (2x + 3) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 8) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{4(x + 2)} + {2}/{(x + 4)} \u003d {3}/{(x + 4)}\\)", "answer": "4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)\n\\({3(x + 4)}/{4} + 2(x + 2) \u003d 3(x + 2)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({3(x + 4)}/{4} + 2(x + 2) - 3(x + 2) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x + 4)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{3(x + 1)} + {4}/{3(x + 1)} \u003d {(2x + 9)}/{(x + 1)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-22", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 1)\n\\({(x + 1)}/{3} + {4(x + 1)}/{3} \u003d (2x + 9)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(x + 1)}/{3} + {4(x + 1)}/{3} - (2x + 9) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x - 22)/3 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-22\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 5)} + {1}/{4(x + 2)} \u003d {2}/{(x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)\n\\((x + 2) + {(x + 5)}/{4} \u003d 2(x + 2)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 2) + {(x + 5)}/{4} - 2(x + 2) \u003d 0\\)\n-3(x + 1)/4 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(2x + 11)} + {1}/{(2x + 3)} \u003d {(4x + 7)}/{(2x + 11)(2x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 11)(2x + 3)\n\\(2(2x + 3) + (2x + 11) \u003d (4x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(2x + 3) + (2x + 11) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(3x + 2)} + {1}/{(x + 1)} \u003d {(3x + 11)}/{(3x + 2)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 2)(x + 1)\n\\((x + 1) + (3x + 2) \u003d (3x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 1) + (3x + 2) - (3x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n(x - 8) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({4}/{(4x + 1)} + {4}/{(2x + 5)} \u003d {2(x + 1)}/{(4x + 1)(2x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(4x + 1)(2x + 5)\n\\(4(2x + 5) + 4(4x + 1) \u003d 2(x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(4(2x + 5) + 4(4x + 1) - 2(x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n22(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(2x + 3)} + {3}/{2(2x + 5)} \u003d {(3x + 8)}/{(2x + 3)(2x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 3)(2x + 5)\n\\({(2x + 5)}/{2} + {3(2x + 3)}/{2} \u003d (3x + 8)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(2x + 5)}/{2} + {3(2x + 3)}/{2} - (3x + 8) \u003d 0\\)\n(x - 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 3)} + {3}/{(x + 1)} \u003d {(4x + 7)}/{(x + 3)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 1)\n\\(2(x + 1) + 3(x + 3) \u003d (4x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 1) + 3(x + 3) - (4x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(3x + 2)} + {2}/{(x + 7)} \u003d {(3x + 7)}/{(3x + 2)(x + 7)}\\)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 2)(x + 7)\n\\(3(x + 7) + 2(3x + 2) \u003d (3x + 7)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 7) + 2(3x + 2) - (3x + 7) \u003d 0\\)\n6(x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{4(x + 2)} + {2}/{3(x + 1)} \u003d {(x + 10)}/{(x + 2)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "19", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 1)\n\\({3(x + 1)}/{4} + {2(x + 2)}/{3} \u003d (x + 10)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({3(x + 1)}/{4} + {2(x + 2)}/{3} - (x + 10) \u003d 0\\)\n5(x - 19)/12 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n19\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 2)} + {1}/{(x + 4)} \u003d {3(x + 1)}/{(x + 2)(x + 4)}\\)", "answer": "3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 4)\n\\((x + 4) + (x + 2) \u003d 3(x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 4) + (x + 2) - 3(x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x + 3) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 4)} + {1}/{(3x + 8)} \u003d {3(x + 1)}/{(x + 4)(3x + 8)}\\)", "answer": "-9", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(3x + 8)\n\\((3x + 8) + (x + 4) \u003d 3(x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((3x + 8) + (x + 4) - 3(x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 9) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-9\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(2x + 9)} + {3}/{(x + 3)} \u003d {(2x + 1)}/{(2x + 9)(x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "-5", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 9)(x + 3)\n\\(3(x + 3) + 3(2x + 9) \u003d (2x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 3) + 3(2x + 9) - (2x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n7(x + 5) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-5\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{2(x + 3)} + {4}/{(x + 10)} \u003d {(4x + 3)}/{(x + 3)(x + 10)}\\)", "answer": "-28", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 3)(x + 10)\n\\({(x + 10)}/{2} + 4(x + 3) \u003d (4x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({(x + 10)}/{2} + 4(x + 3) - (4x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 28)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-28\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 3)} + {3}/{2(x + 1)} \u003d {3}/{(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-7", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)\n\\((x + 1) + {3(x + 3)}/{2} \u003d 3(x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 1) + {3(x + 3)}/{2} - 3(x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x - 7)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-7\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({4}/{(x + 5)} + {3}/{(2x + 1)} \u003d {2}/{(2x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(2x + 1)\n\\(4(2x + 1) + 3(x + 5) \u003d 2(x + 5)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(4(2x + 1) + 3(x + 5) - 2(x + 5) \u003d 0\\)\n9(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(3x + 7)} + {3}/{2(2x + 3)} \u003d {2}/{(3x + 7)}\\)", "answer": "-3", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 7)\n\\((2x + 3) + {3(3x + 7)}/{2} \u003d 2(2x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((2x + 3) + {3(3x + 7)}/{2} - 2(2x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n5(x + 3)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-3\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{(x + 2)} + {1}/{2(x + 1)} \u003d {(3x + 5)}/{(x + 2)(x + 1)}\\)", "answer": "2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(x + 1)\n\\(3(x + 1) + {(x + 2)}/{2} \u003d (3x + 5)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(3(x + 1) + {(x + 2)}/{2} - (3x + 5) \u003d 0\\)\n(x - 2)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(3x + 4)} + {1}/{(2x + 5)} \u003d {(3x + 10)}/{(3x + 4)(2x + 5)}\\)", "answer": "-1", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 4)(2x + 5)\n\\(2(2x + 5) + (3x + 4) \u003d (3x + 10)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(2x + 5) + (3x + 4) - (3x + 10) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x + 1) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-1\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 4)} + {1}/{2(x + 2)} \u003d {(x + 5)}/{(x + 4)(x + 2)}\\)", "answer": "2", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 4)(x + 2)\n\\((x + 2) + {(x + 4)}/{2} \u003d (x + 5)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 2) + {(x + 4)}/{2} - (x + 5) \u003d 0\\)\n(x - 2)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n2\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(3x + 10)} + {2}/{(2x + 7)} \u003d {2(x + 1)}/{(3x + 10)(2x + 7)}\\)", "answer": "-4", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(3x + 10)(2x + 7)\n\\(2(2x + 7) + 2(3x + 10) \u003d 2(x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(2x + 7) + 2(3x + 10) - 2(x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n8(x + 4) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-4\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({3}/{2(x + 5)} + {1}/{(x + 10)} \u003d {(3x + 1)}/{(x + 5)(x + 10)}\\)", "answer": "38", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 10)\n\\({3(x + 10)}/{2} + (x + 5) \u003d (3x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\({3(x + 10)}/{2} + (x + 5) - (3x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(-x + 38)/2 \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n38\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 11)} + {1}/{(x + 11)} \u003d {(x + 3)}/{(x + 11)(x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-15", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 11)(x + 11)\n\\(2(x + 11) + (x + 11) \u003d (x + 3)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 11) + (x + 11) - (x + 3) \u003d 0\\)\n2(x + 15) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-15\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 9)} + {4}/{(2x + 11)} \u003d {2(2x + 1)}/{(x + 9)(2x + 11)}\\)", "answer": "-14", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 9)(2x + 11)\n\\(2(2x + 11) + 4(x + 9) \u003d 2(2x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(2x + 11) + 4(x + 9) - 2(2x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x + 14) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-14\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 5)} + {3}/{(x + 10)} \u003d {(3x + 2)}/{(x + 5)(x + 10)}\\)", "answer": "-23", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 5)(x + 10)\n\\((x + 10) + 3(x + 5) \u003d (3x + 2)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((x + 10) + 3(x + 5) - (3x + 2) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 23) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-23\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({2}/{(x + 1)} + {1}/{(x + 4)} \u003d {(2x + 1)}/{(x + 1)(x + 4)}\\)", "answer": "-8", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 1)(x + 4)\n\\(2(x + 4) + (x + 1) \u003d (2x + 1)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\(2(x + 4) + (x + 1) - (2x + 1) \u003d 0\\)\n(x + 8) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n-8\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"},
  {"type": "jqmath", "question": "Solve for x:\n\\({1}/{(x + 2)} + {4}/{(2x + 3)} \u003d {(2x + 11)}/{(x + 2)(2x + 3)}\\)", "answer": "0", "explanation": "Multiply through by the least common polynomial of the rational expressions,\n(x + 2)(2x + 3)\n\\((2x + 3) + 4(x + 2) \u003d (2x + 11)\\)\nMove all terms onto the same side of the equation\n\\((2x + 3) + 4(x + 2) - (2x + 11) \u003d 0\\)\n4(x) \u003d 0\nSolve the simplified expression for x\n0\nCheck that the answer is valid", "prompt": "x \u003d"}
]}